freepeople.com 2017-04-19

# Help & info: Privacy & Security - Free People Clothing Boutique

## Privacy Policy

Effective Date: April 21, 2016

Thank you for visiting www.FreePeople.com (the “Website”). This privacy and security policy (the “Policy”) explains the information we collect about you on the Website, as well as information collected when you visit our stores or otherwise communicate or interact with Free People, how we use the information, some of the security steps taken to protect the information, and the choices you have to review, revise and/or restrict our usage of this information. This Policy is part of the Terms & Conditions of Use that govern the Website and is binding on all Website users.

**If you have any objections to this Privacy Policy, you should immediately discontinue use of the website.**

## What information do we collect and how do we use it?

FreePeople.com collects information from our customers for a variety of reasons, including as part of our ongoing efforts to provide superior customer service, improve shopping experience and to communicate about products, services and promotions. We collect information such as name, telephone number, email, postal address and payment information (“Personal Information”) that you provide to us when you register an account on our site, place an order, participate in a sweepstakes, promotion or survey, write product reviews, post customer-generated photographs and content, or create product collections, wishlists and other user-generated content. We may use this information collected online to process and fulfill your order. We also collect email addresses at various site locations in order to send you necessary order-related messages such as order confirmation and shipment confirmation notices. We maintain a record of your product interests, purchases and whatever else might enable us or our business partners to enhance and personalize your shopping experience on this or other websites and to send you offers, promotions, or information that we believe may be of interest to you.

In addition, we monitor site use and traffic patterns to improve our web site design and the products and services we offer as well as to determine what offers, promotions or information to send to you.

To serve you better, we may combine Personal Information you give us online, via mobile device, in our stores, or through our customer service call center. We may also combine that information with publicly available information and information we receive from cross-reference with select partners and others. By combining this information, we are better able to communicate with you about our products and services, special events and promotions, and better able to personalize your shopping experience.

## Disclosure of Information

Free People shares information you provide to us when you participate in a sweepstakes or promotion with those companies with whom we have joined to offer the sweepstakes promotion. We may disclose information about you to other members of the Free People corporate family and our business partners. We will also disclose information as we determine to be required by law. In addition, we may on occasion share information with business partners not owned or affiliated with Free People who want to market products or services to you. In the event that a store, division, assets or part or all of Free People is bought, sold or otherwise transferred, or is in the process of a potential transaction, customer information will likely be shared for evaluation purposes and included among the transferred business assets.

We do not share credit card or other payment information with third parties except for the purposes of processing payment for products and services you’ve ordered and as required by law. In addition, we may disclose credit card and other information we collect from you with an outside company with which we have contracted for their services to protect against fraud and the unauthorized use of credit and gift cards.

## Procedures to review your personal information and to opt-out

You can always update your personal information or opt-out of our catalog mailing list or other communications from us. If at any time you would like us to update your information or you opt-out, just [click here](http://www.freepeople.com/contact/) to email FreePeople.com customer service. Please be sure to include your email address, full name and mailing address.

## Business Partners

We contract with outside services to help us and our business partners better understand your use of FreePeople.com. These outside services may use “cookies” or other technologies to collect various kinds of information for us and our business partners related to your use of FreePeople.com, so that we and our business partners may continue to refine and improve this and other sites for our customers. We do not allow these parties to collect any credit card, user name or password information. These services are contractually required to maintain all the information collected for us in conformance with this Policy. As a visitor to FreePeople.com, you may "opt-out" of these types of collection of data. To learn more about your options, [click here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

“Cookies” are bits of information that are automatically stored on your computer. If you do not want to have cookies on your system, you can set your browser to disable them. Kindly note however that if you decline cookies on the Website, some functions on the Website may be limited or unavailable. As a result, to make it easier to use the Website, we recommend that your browser settings accept cookies on the Website.

We or our partners may use Flash Cookies (also known as Local Stored Objects) or other similar technologies. A Flash cookie is a small data file placed on a computer using Adobe Flash or similar technology that may be built into your computer or downloaded or installed by you to your computer. We use these technologies to personalize and enhance your online experience, facilitate processes, personalize and store your settings. Flash cookies may help our website visitors to, for example, set volume preference associated with a video experience, play games and perform surveys. They help us improve our sites by measuring which areas are of greatest interest to customers. They may be recognized by other sites or by our marketing or business partners. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies and the cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. [Click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html) to learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies. If you disable Flash cookies or other similar technologies, please be aware that you may not have access to certain features and services that make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable.

### Do Not Track

Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that users can set in some web browsers, allowing users to opt out of tracking by websites and online services. At the present time, the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) has not yet established universal standards for recognizable DNT signals and therefore, Free People and the Website do not recognize DNT.

## Secure Shopping

We adopt appropriate and industry-standard data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on the Website.

Sensitive personal information contained in orders placed on the Website are encrypted using 128-bit secure sockets layer (SSL) technology.* In order for SSL security to work, you must use an SSL enabled browser. *Secure Socket Layer (SSL) is a technology used by vendors to ensure the security of online business. It negotiates and employs the essential functions of mutual authentication, data encryption and data integrity for secure transactions.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personal Information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through the Website cannot be guaranteed; and (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party.

If you still have concerns about ordering electronically, feel free to call **(800) 309-1500** and place your order over the phone. Have the 8-digit style number, size, and color ready for each item you wish to order. You can also print your shopping basket page and mail it to:

Free People  
4010 Rose Lane  
Augusta, GA 30907  
Attn: Order Processing

Please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered to secure means of transmitting credit card numbers. We will never ask for sensitive Personal Information via e-mail.

**YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE AT ALL TIMES FOR MAINTAINING THE CONFIDENTIALITY OF ANY PASSWORD OR OTHER ACCESS INFORMATION.**

### Children’s Privacy

Our Website is not directed at children. In accordance with federal law, we do not solicit or knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under age 13 without the verifiable permission of a parent or guardian. If Free People learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information online without parental consent, it will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from its databases and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or allowed by law). If you become aware of any personally identifiable information we have collected from children under 13, please contact us as provided below.

### Your California Privacy Rights

This privacy policy describes how we may share your information for marketing purposes, as described above. California residents are entitled to request and obtain from us once per calendar year information about any of your personal information shared with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes, including the categories of information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we have shared such information. To request this information and for any other questions about our privacy practices and compliance with California law, please contact us as explained below.

## Policy Changes

Free People may periodically update this Policy including for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed. Any changes made will be posted here. By visiting and continuing to use the Website you agree to accept any changes made to this Policy. Feel free to contact us with any questions about our Policy.

Or contact us via postal mail:

Free People Direct  
4010 Rose Lane  
Augusta, GA 30907
